This was stuck to your face.
Huh? Oh. Thanks.
Hey, is that any fun?
Huh?
Lying on the floor like that all day long. Is it any fun?
Hmm...
Yeah, it is.
Huh, really?
We're all out of balls now.
For real?
Damn...
Looks like they're at it again.
Messing around with their powers and going too far.
Yeah, I know.
Nagara, do you have one?
Huh?
A power.
If I did, I wouldn't be on the floor like this.
Oh, you wouldn't? Guess not, huh.
I wonder why all of this is happening, anyway.
Everyone else has vanished.
Along with everything except for the school.
What are we going to do about that?
It's messed up all our plans for summer vacation.
Hey, is this a utopia? Or hell?
I don't know.
Whoa, are you gonna do something?
Bathroom.
Oh, okay.
Damn, my stomach's killing me!
Come on, guys! How many windows are you going to break?!
Oh well, what can we do?
Yeah. None of them think ahead,
and they're all pissing me off.
It's not like I don't get it, though.
Huh? Get what?
People who were nothing special yesterday
suddenly gained tremendous power.
Of course they'll want to test themselves to find out what they can do.
Right?
But if things suddenly go back to normal,
this will definitely be on us.
How so?
The teachers will say we neglected our duties as the student council.
If that gets into my permanent record, I'll...
Relax. I'll come up with something.
I won't let them break anything else.
What are you gonna do, though?
Did you see their powers?
I don't care how convincing you are...
Has there ever been a time when I
couldn't do what I set out to achieve?
No, there hasn't.
Except, unlike them, we're completely powerless.
It's all right. I'll come up with something.
Sheep aren't all that bright, after all.
I simply have to show them the way.
What exactly are you going to do?
It's simple.
We just need to make up some new rules.
The rules of this world.
Rules, huh? And you think everyone will follow them?
It's just like soccer—anyone who commits a foul...
...is given a penalty.
Yep.
Ugh, I'm so bored.
I don't have anyone else to talk to besides you.
Then go make some new friends.
Guess I could.
That is, if I developed some kind of useful superpower.
Do you need one? It doesn't really bother me.
Oh? Trying to sound tough?
No, it's not that...
Hey, I've been thinking...
Yeah?
What if it wasn't the city that disappeared?
It might have been us.
This all feels too real to be a dream.
Thinking that way isn't going to solve anything.
What happened happened.
Hey, what's that?
What?
That up there.
The shiny thing.
Uh, I don't see anything.
Huh?
Are you messing with me?
Is something there?
No...
There there, good boy.
We are unable to contact the outside,
and our parents and teachers must be terribly worried.
It's possible that this is a huge affair,
and we might be on the news.
"...and we might be on the news..."
Currently, the school is all alone in this unknown darkness.
Indeed, we are truly adrift.
Further, there are powers and other unreal phenomena that exist here.
And presently, the school is being damaged by these mysterious powers.
This damage is being caused by reckless students
who happened to gain these powers.
Before long, someone will come to rescue us.
However, we have a duty as students of this school.
We must bear in mind that we are in our senior year.
Which is why I have a proposal for you all.
So that everyone can play their part,
we will have duties selected for each of us.
And to assign them, we will need a leader.
This leader will be chosen from among the 36 of us,
and together, we will write the rules of this world!
Congratulations!
As of now, you are our leader!
You really want me to do this?
You're the Student Council president, Machi.
Shouldn't it be you?
No...
It's gotta be you.
All right!
Hey, before summer vacation,
do you remember there being any strange incidents at school?
What do you mean?
During first term,
is it true that some auroras and skyfish showed up in the schoolyard,
and that 300 million yen was found in the lockers?
I think I might have heard something about that.
But if any of that actually happened, wouldn't it—
Hey, Nagara, what are you up to?
Huh?
Aren't you on cleaning duty today?
What do you mean?
Didn't you see the Group Talk?
You did get an invite from Cap, right?
Oh, that. I didn't think it concerned me.
Huh? Are you serious?! You're in for it now.
In for what?
You see, there are some new rules.
Like "No using powers while inside the school."
On top of that, everyone has a duty now.
Rules?
And our leader is in charge of it all!
Leader?
Yeah, Cap!
What's a Group Talk?
For real?!
She doesn't have a smartphone.
Ah, this is such a pain!
Hayato!
Are you slacking off?
Ah, crap. Gotta go.
Make sure to read your messages!
Sure, will do.
Why can't we use our powers?!
Because it's something we all decided together.
Huh? You guys just prompted the rest of them to agree to it.
Majority rules?
Don't make me laugh!
That's quite enough.
You're just jealous because you don't have any proper powers, aren't you?
Huh? What are you laughing at?
I just think it's funny.
Huh?
I mean, of course you're happy.
All of a sudden, you've obtained this incredible power,
when you were just a stooge before.
What did you say?
But you know what?
It's a power that doesn't work in the real world.
On top of that, it has nothing to do with your own worth.
It's just a power that you happened to pick up, right?
You should think a little harder before you act on it.
Hey!
Huh?
You just broke the window, didn't you?!
So what if I did?
That's two now. Am I right?
Yeah, that's right.
Three! Four! Five!
Hey, be careful!
Six!
Yeah! I'll break as many as I like!
"We must not dirty or damage the school.
Let's keep it neat."
Penalty!
The heck is that?
I keep dividing and dividing, but it never ends!
No, no, no!
It's divison hell.
He has to endlessly divide for his penalty!
Like I said...
your word is absolute.
Damn...!
Oh, yeah...
No, I don't want to do this!
Why is this happening to me?
Did you hear about Asakaze?
Yeah. He's being made to do division all night long, right?
Calculating-pi hell. The rules are absolute. Yikes!
Um, I need enough for two.
That is enough for two.
Oh, it is?
Finally found you.
Nozomi, right?
Not cooperating, and doing this...
She's just being spiteful.
Yep.
I hear you just got back from abroad. That's so cool.
Sure did.
This is for you.
I heard from Hayato that you don't have a smartphone.
So we're going to provide you with one.
For starters, I'll need you to join the Group Talk...
I'm good, thanks.
Uh, what did you say?
I don't want it.
And, uh, what exactly do you mean by that?
Do you not like the design of this smartphone? Or is it—
I don't wish to participate. That's what I mean.
S-So you're saying...
You don't approve of what we're doing?
That's right. I don't like how rigid you're being.
Why not let everyone be free?
We can't do that. This is for everyone's sake.
You'll be thanking us before you know it.
This world has to be fair and square.
You see, we're victims.
You talk as if you're God.
And has the world ever really been "fair"?
Thank you.
All right then, goodbye.
Are you just going to let her walk away, Cap?!
"We must not break school supplies."
No... Just a moment!
Penalty!
What, is that your power?
I still... see it...
Is she being penalized, too?
Yeah. Hundred-laps-around-the-school hell.
Damn these stupid rules.
There must be some way around that idiot's power.
Dwelling on it won't help.
Why not?
Because rules are rules.
Must be nice to think that way. Do you have a power?
Does it look like I do?
Guess not.
First, the mystery of this darkness.
No matter what we do,
we cannot observe what's outside.
It's an absolute void.
It appears that time is still
moving forward within the school...
It may still be flowing,
but are we truly in its flow?
If not, then her arm will never heal,
and we won't ever grow another millimeter.
That being said, I do get hungry,
and still require sleep.
I don't understand.
To top it all off, there are these powers.
It's positively absurd!
I can't comprehend this phenomenon.
We really might be adrift in here.
This world, as he refers to it,
is structured differently to the real world,
as are the "rules" of this world.
So the real question is...
How did this happen, anyway?
I was on my way to the library to
borrow a book, and at that moment...
Oh yeah!
That's when that storm hit!
Huh?
Is the school... sinking?
I'm sorry.
You have nothing to apologize for.
But this is the third time now.
I'm sure your mother has her reasons.
It might sound strange to you,
but things have been tough for us adults lately too.
Right.
Hey, Ms. Aki,
would you mind faxing this for me?
'Kay!
But you see...
While your career pathway certainly is important,
what I'm most concerned about is your mental health.
You aren't alone. I'm here for you.
You can come talk to me about anything, okay?
Thank you.
I'm glad to have you as my homeroom teacher.
Are you a third-year?
Yeah, I am.
So am I. The name's Nozomi.
And you're Nagara, right?
Huh? How'd you know?
That's just dandy.
Hey, you wanna join me?
No, I'm good.
Really? It feels great.
Why are you tearing it up?
Huh? Just because.
Come on, go for it. It's fun.
No, I don't want to.
Because the teachers will get mad at you?
I have to go.
Leaving?
I've got stuff to do.
Yeah, I know people like you.
Always pretending they're busy.
Acting like they have so many places they need to be.
Yet they always seem to be the ones who have nowhere to go.
Hey, do you...
Do you really want to go somewhere?
Nagara, hold on. I'm not done talking to you.
Hey, are you running away from me?!
What's that you're doing there?
What do you mean?
We still have exams when we get back.
When we get back?
What?!
What's happening?!
As of now, we're taking control of the school.
Huh? Don't be ridiculous!
You'll get another penalty—
We're sick of listening to you.
Huh? What?
Oh...
Huh?
You're not the only ones who gained powers.
Where are you going?
I'm leaving this world.
Huh? Hold on...
Are you sure you want to do this?
Penalty!
Hey, this isn't how you said it'd go!
You said we wouldn't get penalties!
Penalty!
I'm not done yet!
You've been like this ever since grade school.
Huh?
You've always needed to have some kind of authority.
What'd you say?!
I mean, just because you can play a little baseball,
people fawn over you.
You only got nominated because of Hoshi.
Sh-Shut up!
Penalty!
Wh-Why?!
I knew it!
I haven't broken any of the rules this time.
This isn't your power at all. It's just the way things are.
It's the power of this world, isn't it?
Rules are aggressively enforced in this space.
To put it another way...
You have no power here!
I won't have any of this disobedience!
Good grief...
How do we get out of here?
It might be surprisingly easy, if we just give it a try.
Hey, did you have to go that far?!
Huh?!
Oh, nothing.
Hands off! I don't care about the rules.
I have a duty to uphold here.
Are you sure you want to be doing this?
Huh?
So it's okay for you to break the school's rules?
Of course it is.
I'm the captain, after all.
No.
Huh?
It isn't.
No exceptions.
Huh?
Penalty!
Poor guy. He was only trying to perform his duties.
What does this mean? The leader isn't the only one who can give out penalties?
It wasn't something you needed to know.
You all just had to keep quiet and do as you were told.
You bastard!
You really are an idiot. No imagination at all.
You don't understand a thing unless you're given a simple demonstration.
None of you can return to the world you came from.
This is the place, all right.
I can see it clearly.
There had to have been a bird here.
But it's not here anymore.
It must have returned to its own world.
So, um, what are you...
Tell me, are you a sunflower, or are you a dandelion?
Huh? What are you talking about?
If you knew of a place that was brighter than where you were,
would you want to go see it?
Or would you stay where you are
and stare at it from afar?
If I had to choose...
Yeah?
Dandelion, I guess.
Then you're like me.
What is she doing?